let's look at the solution to our
virtual memory quiz we said that the
computer has 16 active applications each
with a 32-bit address space so each
potentially sees a four gigabyte memory
what is the real memory in the system it
turns out that all of these are
potentially correct we can have a system
that has only 2 2 gigabyte memory
modules so it really has a total of 4
gigabyte physical memory yet it can run
16 applications each of which thinks
that it has 4 gigabytes of memory we can
also have more memory even more memory
the different combination of memory and
so on so pretty much what the
applications think they have in terms of
memory and what the system really has
can be completely decoupled by virtual
memory